nationaljewish.org 2009-12-20

# Web Site Privacy and Security - National Jewish Health

National Jewish Health  
Attention: Webmaster, M310  
1400 Jackson Street  
Denver, CO 80206 

**E-mail:** [Webmaster@njhealth.org](mailto:Webmaster@njhealth.org)   
**Phone: (303) 398-1759**

## Our Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy is very important to National Jewish Health. This Web site Privacy and Security statement describes Web site security measures we have in place to protect your information as well as the information we collect on this Web site and how we use it. Our overarching promise to our Web site visitors is that we will not sell your information-including your e-mail, data on your Web site usage or personal medical information-to anyone, and we will only share it within National Jewish Health or with partner medical providers if you have authorized us to do so. National Jewish Health complies completely and consistently with the United States Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) law in regards to your personal medical information-we keep it secure and private, and only share it for reasons of medical service and research. If you have questions about National Jewish Health Web site privacy and security, please feel free to contact us by the postal mail address, e-mail address, or phone number shown above, and we'll be happy to assist you.   

## Web Site Security

When we transfer and receive sensitive information from Web site visitors such as financial or medical information, we redirect visitors to a secure server using state-of-the-art encryption technology. We do this so that if this information is intercepted, it is not easily readable. We only send your personal information to medical service provider partners with whom we have written contracts that require them to keep your information private. And we have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our Web site. 

## Your Information and How We Use It 

We may collect anonymous information about Web site visitors, and we use that to help us improve the Web site. If we do collect personal information such as your e-mail address, phone number, or credit card, we only do so when you actively choose to enter that information into our Web site, and we maintain tight, advanced security for that information. In any situation, we never sell your information (whether anonymous or personally identifiable) to anyone. And if we do share Web site visitor information with any other organizations, it is to that we can provide you a medical or business service, and we ensure that those organizations hold your information as securely as we do. 

  * **E-mail Addresses**   
We do not collect visitors' e-mail address unless they actively provide them. If visitors do provide e-mail addresses, we do not rent or exchange those e-mail addresses. E-mail addresses provided by site visitors who contact National Jewish Health by completing the Lung Line e-mail contact form may be provided to other departments within National Jewish Health. This is so those National Jewish Health departments may contact those visitors for hospital business purposes. Visitors are able to opt out of this contact on the Lung Line form itself if they do not wish to be contacted other than in direct response to their e-mail request. 
  * **Protected Health Information**   
Information about you, your health, and the healthcare services you receive is called "protected health information," or PHI. National Jewish Health is required by the United States Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) law to keep this information private, whether we learned this information about you from our Web site, phone, e-mail or on-site at our facilities. Your National Jewish Health healthcare team will use your PHI to manage your care. We will use your PHI to communicate with other healthcare providers, such as your referring physician, and to contact you for appointment reminders. We will also use your PHI to obtain payment and to support hospital operations. In general, we use as little PHI as necessary for these purposes in order to protect it. Learn more about how National Jewish Health will use and protect your PHI. 
  * **Cookies  
** We may collect cookies from our Web site visitors. A cookie is a text file that our computer places on each visitor's web browser. Cookies tell us non-personally-identifiable information about our visitors such as what browsers and computer operating systems they use, and ways that they use our Web site, such as what pages they visit and how long they stay on certain web page. We do not use this information in a way that identifies you - we use it to help us improve our Web site's experience for visitors and "remember" them so that we can serve information that is tailored to the way they use the Web site. You can always delete and block cookies through your Internet browser. Each browser has a different but often simple way to do this-to find out how, search your browser's "Help" section. Please note that if you delete or block cookies, you may limit some of the capabilities of this Web site. Learn more about [cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie). 

## Future Use of Web Site Visitor Information

From time to time, we may use Web site visitor information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed here. If our information practices change at some time in the future, we will post the policy changes to this page, date them and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. 

## More Information

If you'd like more information about our Web site's privacy and security, please contact us at the e-mail, postal address, or phone number at the top of this page. We would be happy to speak with you. Or see: 

Uses and Disclosures of Your Protected Health Information

Professional Education Privacy Policy and Practices ****
